<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>migration on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/migration/</link><description>Recent content in migration on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/migration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog Migration Details</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/113-blog-migration-details/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/113-blog-migration-details/</guid><description>The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer&amp;rsquo;s Blog I&amp;rsquo;m getting really lazy in my old age, so what I&amp;rsquo;ve posted here is just the meager README.md file from my blog&amp;rsquo;s new GitHub repo.
This project, my Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer&amp;rsquo;s blog, is no longer a Docker &amp;ldquo;Multi-Stage&amp;rdquo; build.
GitHub Pages I successfully moved this blog to GitHub Pages in October 2021, after creating instances of it on DigitalOcean and Azure. GH Pages, specifically https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/ seems like the right home for it, finally.</description></item><item><title>DG's ISLE Git Workflow</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/053-dgs-isle-git-workflow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/053-dgs-isle-git-workflow/</guid><description>For some time now Digital.Grinnell has been using ISLE in production, with an instance that was built from a &amp;ldquo;non-standard&amp;rdquo; workflow, one that was a little different than the Git workflow established in the ISLE install docs. Consequently, DG&amp;rsquo;s situation is a little different than what&amp;rsquo;s documented for ISLE, so my mission here is to describe and execute the steps I&amp;rsquo;m taking to get back into the documented workflow.
The steps will involve and achieve the following:
Establish a working, local instance of my production DG site with an ISLE-1.</description></item><item><title>Migrating Digital.Grinnell (DG) to ISLE 1.3.0 (ld) for Local Development</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/051-migrating-dg-to-isle-1.3.0-ld/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/051-migrating-dg-to-isle-1.3.0-ld/</guid><description>This is a follow-up to previous posts 034, Building ISLE 1.2.0 (ld) and 037, Migrating Digital.Grinnell (DG) to ISLE 1.2.0 (ld) for Local Development where I successfully completed a &amp;ldquo;local&amp;rdquo; build of ISLE v1.2.0 and subsequently started &amp;ldquo;customization&amp;rdquo; of that local instance. So, this post&amp;rsquo;s intent is to complete the goal stated in Migrating Digital.Grinnell (DG) to ISLE 1.2.0 (ld) for Local Development, but for ISLE 1.3.0, specifically to:
The goal of this project is to spin up a pristine, local Islandora stack using an updated fork of the ISLE project at https://github.</description></item><item><title>Migrating Digital.Grinnell (DG) to ISLE 1.2.0 (ld) for Local Development</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/037-migrating-dg-to-isle-1.2.0-ld/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/037-migrating-dg-to-isle-1.2.0-ld/</guid><description>This post is a follow-up to previous post 034 where I successfully completed a &amp;ldquo;local&amp;rdquo; build of ISLE v1.2.0, but did no &amp;ldquo;customization&amp;rdquo; of that local instance. So, this post&amp;rsquo;s intent is to complete the goal stated in post 034, specifically to:
The goal of this project is to spin up a pristine, local Islandora stack using an updated fork of the ISLE project at https://github.com/DigitalGrinnell/dg-isle, then introduce elements like the Digital Grinnell theme and custom modules like DG7. Once these pieces are in-place and working, I&amp;rsquo;ll begin adding other critical components as well as a robust set of data gleaned from https://digital.</description></item></channel></rss>