<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>migration on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/migration/</link><description>Recent content in migration on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/migration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrating CATPAW Development to Azure</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/135-migrating-catpaw-development-to-azure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/135-migrating-catpaw-development-to-azure/</guid><description>Portions of this post build on concepts introduced in Managing Azure.
CATPAW - Computer-Aided Thinking, Primarily about Writing From the CATPAW home screen&amp;hellip;
In many ways, CATPAW is an online book about writing style&amp;ndash;a guide to the choices we make in writing that connect us to our readers.
Rather than setting out rules to follow, CATPAW will help you make informed choices in context. The site accomplishes that goal in three ways:
It explains the choices writers face. It uses computational tools to help you examine your own writing, letting you see what choices you have already made and what you might want to do differently.</description></item><item><title>Creating a CollectionBuilder-CSV Instance from Our Migration Collection</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/134-creating-a-collectionbuilder-csv-instance-from-our-migration-collection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/134-creating-a-collectionbuilder-csv-instance-from-our-migration-collection/</guid><description>This post is essentially a CollectionBuilder-CSV follow-up to Creating a Migration Collection, intended to document the path I&amp;rsquo;ve taken and the decisions I made when creating a first cut of Digital.Grinnell content using the aformentioned CollectionBuilder-CSV.
CB-CSV_DG-01 With few notable exceptions, everything mentioned below will be visible in a new public GitHub repo at Digital-Grinnell/CB-CSV_DG-01.
Corresponding Google Sheet One of the exceptions: the project&amp;rsquo;s metadata CSV in a time-stamped tab at https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1ic4PxHDbuzDrmf4YtauhC4vEQJxt3QSH8bYfLBCM3Gc/.
Other worksheets/tabs in the Google Sheet contain:
Sheet 1 = the initial imported demo data from the CollectionBuilder-CSV Metadata Template</description></item><item><title>Creating a Migration Collection</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/129-creating-a-migration-collection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/129-creating-a-migration-collection/</guid><description>As we continue to look at potential migration paths for our Digital.Grinnell (DG) content, it&amp;rsquo;s become apparent that it would be nice to have a small &amp;ldquo;test&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;migration&amp;rdquo; collection of objects to play with. The collection should have a small, but diverse, set of objects covering all of the popular content, or CModel, types that we currently have in DG.
Since Slack now imposes a 90-day lifespan for posts (we are using only free-tier Slack services at this time) I thought I had better create this blog post to capture key parts of a relevant Slack conversation&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Blog Migration Details</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/113-blog-migration-details/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/113-blog-migration-details/</guid><description>The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer&amp;rsquo;s Blog I&amp;rsquo;m getting really lazy in my old age, so what I&amp;rsquo;ve posted here is just the meager README.md file from my blog&amp;rsquo;s new GitHub repo.
This project, my Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer&amp;rsquo;s blog, is no longer a Docker &amp;ldquo;Multi-Stage&amp;rdquo; build.
GitHub Pages I successfully moved this blog to GitHub Pages in October 2021, after creating instances of it on DigitalOcean and Azure. GH Pages, specifically https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/ seems like the right home for it, finally.</description></item><item><title>DG's ISLE Git Workflow</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/053-dgs-isle-git-workflow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/053-dgs-isle-git-workflow/</guid><description>For some time now Digital.Grinnell has been using ISLE in production, with an instance that was built from a &amp;ldquo;non-standard&amp;rdquo; workflow, one that was a little different than the Git workflow established in the ISLE install docs. Consequently, DG&amp;rsquo;s situation is a little different than what&amp;rsquo;s documented for ISLE, so my mission here is to describe and execute the steps I&amp;rsquo;m taking to get back into the documented workflow.
The steps will involve and achieve the following:
Establish a working, local instance of my production DG site with an ISLE-1.</description></item><item><title>Migrating Digital.Grinnell (DG) to ISLE 1.3.0 (ld) for Local Development</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/051-migrating-dg-to-isle-1.3.0-ld/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/051-migrating-dg-to-isle-1.3.0-ld/</guid><description>This is a follow-up to previous posts 034, Building ISLE 1.2.0 (ld) and 037, Migrating Digital.Grinnell (DG) to ISLE 1.2.0 (ld) for Local Development where I successfully completed a &amp;ldquo;local&amp;rdquo; build of ISLE v1.2.0 and subsequently started &amp;ldquo;customization&amp;rdquo; of that local instance. So, this post&amp;rsquo;s intent is to complete the goal stated in Migrating Digital.Grinnell (DG) to ISLE 1.2.0 (ld) for Local Development, but for ISLE 1.3.0, specifically to:
The goal of this project is to spin up a pristine, local Islandora stack using an updated fork of the ISLE project at https://github.</description></item><item><title>Migrating Digital.Grinnell (DG) to ISLE 1.2.0 (ld) for Local Development</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/037-migrating-dg-to-isle-1.2.0-ld/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/037-migrating-dg-to-isle-1.2.0-ld/</guid><description>This post is a follow-up to previous post 034 where I successfully completed a &amp;ldquo;local&amp;rdquo; build of ISLE v1.2.0, but did no &amp;ldquo;customization&amp;rdquo; of that local instance. So, this post&amp;rsquo;s intent is to complete the goal stated in post 034, specifically to:
The goal of this project is to spin up a pristine, local Islandora stack using an updated fork of the ISLE project at https://github.com/DigitalGrinnell/dg-isle, then introduce elements like the Digital Grinnell theme and custom modules like DG7. Once these pieces are in-place and working, I&amp;rsquo;ll begin adding other critical components as well as a robust set of data gleaned from https://digital.</description></item></channel></rss>