<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>collection on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/collection/</link><description>Recent content in collection on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/collection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a Migration Collection</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/129-creating-a-migration-collection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/129-creating-a-migration-collection/</guid><description>As we continue to look at potential migration paths for our Digital.Grinnell (DG) content, it&amp;rsquo;s become apparent that it would be nice to have a small &amp;ldquo;test&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;migration&amp;rdquo; collection of objects to play with. The collection should have a small, but diverse, set of objects covering all of the popular content, or CModel, types that we currently have in DG.
Since Slack now imposes a 90-day lifespan for posts (we are using only free-tier Slack services at this time) I thought I had better create this blog post to capture key parts of a relevant Slack conversation&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>How to Add a Collection to Digital.Grinnell</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/084-how-to-add-a-collection-to-digital-grinnell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/084-how-to-add-a-collection-to-digital-grinnell/</guid><description>So, you want to add a new collection or sub-collection (they are really the same thing) to Digital.Grinnell, eh? It&amp;rsquo;s easy, but there are some things to consider before I show you how.
Collection Guidelines There are no &amp;ldquo;formal&amp;rdquo; guidelines for the creation of a collection or sub-collection in Digital.Grinnell, but I can think of a couple &amp;ldquo;informal&amp;rdquo; things to consider.
Are there or will there ever be enough objects, old and/or new, with something in common to warrant a new collection?</description></item></channel></rss>