<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hugo on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in hugo on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog Migration Details</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/113-blog-migration-details/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/113-blog-migration-details/</guid><description>The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer&amp;rsquo;s Blog I&amp;rsquo;m getting really lazy in my old age, so what I&amp;rsquo;ve posted here is just the meager README.md file from my blog&amp;rsquo;s new GitHub repo.
This project, my Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer&amp;rsquo;s blog, is no longer a Docker &amp;ldquo;Multi-Stage&amp;rdquo; build.
GitHub Pages I successfully moved this blog to GitHub Pages in October 2021, after creating instances of it on DigitalOcean and Azure. GH Pages, specifically https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/ seems like the right home for it, finally.</description></item><item><title>Moving Static Sites to GitHub Pages</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/112-moving-static-sites-to-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/112-moving-static-sites-to-github-pages/</guid><description>Pertinent Resources This section simply tabluates the posts and documentation used to effect migration of all sites from the Grinnell College static host to GitHub Pages.
Resource Address Hugo: Host on GitHub https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-github/ GitHub: Getting started with GitHub Pages https://docs.github.com/en/pages/getting-started-with-github-pages GitHub: Creating a GitHub Pages site https://docs.github.com/en/pages/getting-started-with-github-pages/creating-a-github-pages-site GitHub: Managing a custom domain for your GitHub Pages site https://docs.github.com/en/pages/configuring-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site/managing-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site#configuring-a-subdomain Customizations Do NOT Set publishDir = &amp;quot;docs&amp;quot; Do NOT change the publishDir parameter in your configuration, if you even have one!</description></item><item><title>Collaborating on Hugo Site Development</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/095-collaborating-on-hugo-site-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/095-collaborating-on-hugo-site-development/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve nearly completed migration of all Grinnell College Libraries&amp;rsquo; static sites to Azure and I&amp;rsquo;m updating this post to reflect that move. Wherever possible I&amp;rsquo;ll strike-through outdated information like this, and replace it with updated info.
This post will instruct the reader to install necessary tools and engage the workflow I now use to develop and maintain a handful of Hugo static websites. The list of sites now includes both professional, those owned and operated by Grinnell College, as well as &amp;ldquo;personal&amp;rdquo; sites that I develop, maintain and host myself.</description></item><item><title>Scheduled Updates for a Hugo Static Site</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/086-scheduled-updates-for-a-hugo-static-site/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 16:56:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/086-scheduled-updates-for-a-hugo-static-site/</guid><description>A few months ago I migrated a site, The Compass Rose Band, from Drupal to Hugo for my Uncle. Since then I have been maintaining the site, adding and removing dates, and updating the site about every other week. With the passage of time events on the site &amp;ldquo;automatically&amp;rdquo; move from &amp;ldquo;upcoming&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;past&amp;rdquo;, but since it is a &amp;ldquo;static&amp;rdquo; site, that only happens when I recompile and rebuild the site. So I needed to automate builds.
I tried a few different ideas I&amp;rsquo;d heard about, including crontab, but on my Mac desktop I ended up settling on an Automator workflow tied to a Calendar event.</description></item><item><title>New Blog Style and Features</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/067-new-blog-style-and-features/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/067-new-blog-style-and-features/</guid><description>Welcome to my new blog theme/style with new features. All of the content, aka &amp;lsquo;posts&amp;rsquo;, from my old blog have been moved here, but there are still lots of remnants of the new theme, Zzo, lurking here. Please be patient with this new format while I work to fully implement all the features that this setup provides.
Also, thank you, Mackenzie. My daughter played an important role in helping me with this transition.
And it&amp;rsquo;s time to do some real work&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll be back to share more here soon.</description></item><item><title>Hugo, Goldmark and CommonMark Compliance</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/061-hugo-and-commmonmark-compliance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/061-hugo-and-commmonmark-compliance/</guid><description>Just making a note here that Hugo, as of version 0.60.0, is now using the Goldmark markdown rendering library, and that library is CommonMark compliant. The official word, from this document states that:
Goldmark is from Hugo 0.60 the default library used for Markdown. It’s fast, it’s CommonMark compliant and it’s very flexible. Note that the feature set of Goldmark vs Blackfriday isn’t the same; you gain a lot but also lose some, but we will work to bridge any gap in the upcoming Hugo versions.</description></item><item><title>CanonifyURLs in Hugo</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/035-canonifyurls-in-hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/035-canonifyurls-in-hugo/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been seeing a lot of .URL will be deprecated... warnings in my Hugo compilations lately, and just now figured out a slick replacement for it: canonifyURLs = true. The documentation for this parameter says&amp;hellip;
By default, all relative URLs encountered in the input are left unmodified, e.g. /css/foo.css would stay as /css/foo.css. The canonifyURLs field in your site config has a default value of false.
By setting canonifyURLs to true, all relative URLs would instead be canonicalized using baseURL. For example, assuming you have baseURL = https://example.</description></item><item><title>Adding a LastMod Date</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/033-adding-lastmod-date/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/033-adding-lastmod-date/</guid><description>So, Hugo supports the use of front matter &amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo; variables including: date, publishDate and lastmod. I won&amp;rsquo;t explain the details of each variable because the aforementioned resource has a nice, concise explanation of them all.
Until recently this blog only dealt with the &amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo; field since I used to have Atom configured to automatically update that field for me when I save changes to a file. However, Hugo treats &amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo; more like the date of publication (publishDate) than the last modification (lastmod) date, so things got a little screwy if/when I edited an old post.</description></item><item><title>Awesome Hugo Resource - Config Variables Summary</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/022-awesome-hugo-resource-config-variables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/022-awesome-hugo-resource-config-variables/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working remotely from a desk on the 3rd floor of the MSOE (Milwaukee School of Engineering) this morning and just ran into a problem with this blog&amp;hellip; some of my single and double quotes are rendered as &amp;ldquo;curly quotes&amp;rdquo; so I can&amp;rsquo;t effectively copy and paste them into a command line. While searching for a fix I found an awesome Hugo resource. It lists, among other things, ALL of Hugo&amp;rsquo;s standard configuration variables!
The settings I&amp;rsquo;m most interested in right now are part of BlackFriday, Hugo&amp;rsquo;s markdown rendering engine.</description></item><item><title>A Blog is Born</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/001-a-blog-is-born/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/001-a-blog-is-born/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered how a blog is born? The story behind this blog begins with my interest in stepping back from the CMS world, primarily Drupal, to discover the joys of static site generation. The journey begins in earnest at the 2016 DLF Forum: Milwaukee on the eve of the United States&amp;rsquo; 2016 national election, when all the buzz that wasn&amp;rsquo;t political, was about building static web sites, and Jekyll.
A few weeks after the DLF Forum this server was born, thanks to the my colleagues in the Grinnell College (GC) Libraries, and Grinnell&amp;rsquo;s Information Technology Services (ITS) department.</description></item></channel></rss>