<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Atom on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/atom/</link><description>Recent content in Atom on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/atom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrating Workflows from Atom to VSCode</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/123-migrating-workflows-from-atom-to-vscode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/123-migrating-workflows-from-atom-to-vscode/</guid><description>&lt;p>This might just be my shortest post ever in this blog, at least for now. At this early date it&amp;rsquo;s just a link to the &lt;a href="https://blog.summittdweller.com/posts/2022/06/atom-no-more/">Atom No More?&lt;/a> blog post in my personal blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The note above indicates that this post superseeds &lt;code>085-remote-atom&lt;/code>, but there are other &lt;em>Atom&lt;/em>-related posts that are also impacted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some of these include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="posts/033-adding-lastmod-date/">posts/033-adding-lastmod-date/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As time passes I&amp;rsquo;ll document here any work-specific changes I make to my new &lt;em>VSCode&lt;/em> environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="replacing-atom--with-code-">Replacing &lt;code>atom .&lt;/code> with &lt;code>code .&lt;/code>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The personal blog post mentioned above, &lt;a href="https://blog.summittdweller.com/posts/2022/06/atom-no-more/">Atom No More?&lt;/a>, includes a procedure I used to implement &lt;code>code .&lt;/code> to launch &lt;em>VSCode&lt;/em> from a terminal window on any of my Mac workstations. As of this writing, June 22, 2022, I have successfully implmented this change on all of my Grinnell College workstations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Remote Atom</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/085-remote-atom/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/085-remote-atom/</guid><description>&lt;p>Earlier this year I installed and configured the &lt;a href="https://atom.io/packages/remote-atom">remote-atom&lt;/a> package to assist with editing content and code for my &lt;a href="https://blog.summittdweller.com">personal blog&lt;/a>. Naturally, I wrote a &lt;a href="https://blog.summittdweller.com/posts/2020/03/adding-remote-atom-to-my-digitalocean-server/">blog post&lt;/a> to document it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the past week I&amp;rsquo;ve added the &lt;strong>remote-atom&lt;/strong> package, and configuration to many of my &lt;a href="https://digital.grinnell.edu">Digital.Grinnell&lt;/a> servers. The installation and configuration was virtually identical to what I described in &lt;a href="https://blog.summittdweller.com/posts/2020/03/adding-remote-atom-to-my-digitalocean-server/">Adding remote-atom to my DigitalOcean Server&lt;/a>. Thus far the package and it&amp;rsquo;s configuration have been implemented on the following workstations, both personal and professional, with the following username@server configurations:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Collaborating on Hugo Site Development</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/095-collaborating-on-hugo-site-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/095-collaborating-on-hugo-site-development/</guid><description>&lt;div class="original">&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve nearly completed migration of all &lt;em>Grinnell College Libraries&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em> static sites to &lt;em>Azure&lt;/em> and I&amp;rsquo;m updating this post to reflect that move. Wherever possible I&amp;rsquo;ll strike-through outdated information &lt;strike>like this&lt;/strike>, and replace it with updated info.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>This post will instruct the reader to install necessary tools and engage the workflow I now use to develop and maintain a handful of &lt;em>Hugo&lt;/em> static websites. The list of sites now includes both professional, those owned and operated by &lt;a href="https://grinnell.edu">Grinnell College&lt;/a>, as well as &amp;ldquo;personal&amp;rdquo; sites that I develop, maintain and host myself.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>