<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WARC on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/warc/</link><description>Recent content in WARC on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/warc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a WARC from a Wordpress Clone</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/126-creating-a-warc-from-a-wordpress-clone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/126-creating-a-warc-from-a-wordpress-clone/</guid><description>This blog post chronicles portions of a process used to restore and subsequently WARC (the creation of a web archive) a Communication Department website that had been retired. The website content of interest included material describing plans for the recently-completed HSSC and Administration Building projects.
During the restoration and WARC process a .md document named WARC-from-comm.sites.grinnell.edu-clone.md was created and it&amp;rsquo;s contents are presented here.
Creating a WARC from a Clone of comm.sites.grinnell.edu In July 2022 a new &amp;ldquo;clone&amp;rdquo; of the original comm.</description></item><item><title>Here There Be WARCs</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/082-here-there-be-warcs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/082-here-there-be-warcs/</guid><description>The term WARC, an abbreviation of Web ARChive, always reminds me of things like hobbits, elves, dark lords, and orcs, of course. But this post has nothing to do with those things so I need to clear my head and press on.
A WARC is essentially a file format used to capture the content and organization of a web site. Recently, I was asked to add a pair of WARCs to Digital.Grinnell. Doing so proved to be quite an adventure, but I am pleased to report that we now have these two objects to show for it:</description></item></channel></rss>