<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VSCode on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/vscode/</link><description>Recent content in VSCode on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/vscode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VSCode Find and Replace Using `regex`</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/128-vscode-find-and-replace-using-regex/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/128-vscode-find-and-replace-using-regex/</guid><description>This morning I needed to do some bulk &amp;ldquo;find and replace&amp;rdquo; operations in most of my Rootstalk content. My first thought was to write and run a little Python script, but then I wondered what VSCode might bring to the table. Plenty, it brought plenty!
To keep this post as brief as possible, I&amp;rsquo;m simply going to reference an instructional video that I created earlier: VSCode-Find-and-Replace.mp4.
A list of some links mentioned in the video is provided here:
https://linuxpip.org/vscode-regex-replace/ https://itnext.io/vscode-find-and-replace-regex-super-powers-c7f8be0fa80f https://www.</description></item><item><title>Migrating Workflows from Atom to VSCode</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/123-migrating-workflows-from-atom-to-vscode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/123-migrating-workflows-from-atom-to-vscode/</guid><description>This might just be my shortest post ever in this blog, at least for now. At this early date it&amp;rsquo;s just a link to the Atom No More? blog post in my personal blog.
The note above indicates that this post superseeds 085-remote-atom, but there are other Atom-related posts that are also impacted.
Some of these include:
posts/033-adding-lastmod-date/ As time passes I&amp;rsquo;ll document here any work-specific changes I make to my new VSCode environments.
Replacing atom . with code . The personal blog post mentioned above, Atom No More?</description></item></channel></rss>