<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>XSLT on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/xslt/</link><description>Recent content in XSLT on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 13:20:16 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/xslt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Digital.Grinnell Transforms</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/114-digital.grinnell-transforms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/114-digital.grinnell-transforms/</guid><description>Digital.Grinnell relies on two different metadata XSL &amp;ldquo;transforms&amp;rdquo; to convert a cataloger&amp;rsquo;s MODS descriptive data into a modified MODS record and a corresponding Dublin Core record.
Self-Transforms The first transform type can be thought of as a &amp;ldquo;self-transform&amp;rdquo; because it accepts a MODS input and produces a modified MODS output; there is no change in schema, just changes in the data and its order.
MODS-to-DC Transforms All other transforms relevant to this document are &amp;ldquo;MODS-to-DC&amp;rdquo; transforms. They accept a valid MODS record and output a corresponding, valid record under the DC schema.</description></item><item><title>Missing Oral History Transcripts in DG - Fixed</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/026-oral-history-solr-fix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 13:09:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/026-oral-history-solr-fix/</guid><description>I recently constructed a new, local/development instance of ISLE (see my previous post) largely in order to debug a mystery in Digital.Grinnell&amp;rsquo;s display of oral histories. My Trello card for the issue reads:
Our newest AOH entries, and some older objects, will not display a transcript after upgrade to the latest version of the OH module. OHScribe is needed to aid in re-processing transcripts for these objects, and some XDebug work will also be required.
Engaging XDebug and PHPStorm allowed me to peek inside the relatively complex oral histories (OH) module where I found that some of our OH objects were missing key Solr field elements, like or_transcripts and or_speaker.</description></item></channel></rss>