<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>islandora_datastream_replace on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/islandora_datastream_replace/</link><description>Recent content in islandora_datastream_replace on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/islandora_datastream_replace/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IDU DiffDatastreamVersions Command</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/118-new-idu-diffdatastreamversions-command/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/118-new-idu-diffdatastreamversions-command/</guid><description>Recently, I have been catching up on processing some pending metadata review edits in DG&amp;rsquo;s Faculty Scholarship and Student Scholarship collections. Since these two collections are relatively &amp;ldquo;fluid&amp;rdquo;, they get frequent additions and metadata changes, I was worried that introducing bulk edits could negatively impact some objects. So I set out to find, or create, a tool that would help me evaluate the impact of these edits.
Islandora Pretty Text Diff I was fortunate to find a very nice tool all ready-to-go, the Islandora Pretty Text Diff module, specifically islandora_pretty_text_diff.</description></item><item><title>Exporting, Editing &amp; Replacing MODS Datastreams: Updated Technical Details</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/115-exporting-editing-replacing-mods-datastreams-updated-technical-details/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/115-exporting-editing-replacing-mods-datastreams-updated-technical-details/</guid><description>Attention: On 21-May-2020 an optional, but recommended, sixth step was added to this workflow in the form of a new _Drush_ command: _islandora\_mods_post\_processing_, an addition to my previous work in [islandora_mods_via_twig](https://github.com/DigitalGrinnell/islandora_mods_via_twig). See my new post, [Islandora MODS Post Processing](/posts/075-islandora-mods-post-processing/) for complete details. Attention: In November 2021 a recommended seventh step was added to this workflow. That addition is documented in the final section of this document. A 7-Step Workflow This document is follow-up, with technical details, to Exporting, Editing &amp;amp; Replacing MODS Datastreams, post 069, in my blog.</description></item><item><title>Here There Be WARCs</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/082-here-there-be-warcs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/082-here-there-be-warcs/</guid><description>The term WARC, an abbreviation of Web ARChive, always reminds me of things like hobbits, elves, dark lords, and orcs, of course. But this post has nothing to do with those things so I need to clear my head and press on.
A WARC is essentially a file format used to capture the content and organization of a web site. Recently, I was asked to add a pair of WARCs to Digital.Grinnell. Doing so proved to be quite an adventure, but I am pleased to report that we now have these two objects to show for it:</description></item><item><title>Exporting, Editing, &amp; Replacing MODS Datastreams: Technical Details</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/070-exporting-editing-replacing-mods-datastreams-technical-details/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/070-exporting-editing-replacing-mods-datastreams-technical-details/</guid><description>Attention: On 21-May-2020 an optional, but recommended, sixth step was added to this workflow in the form of a new Drush command: islandora_mods_post_processing, an addition to my previous work in islandora_mods_via_twig. See my new post, Islandora MODS Post Processing for complete details.
A 5-Step Workflow This document is follow-up, with technical details, to Exporting, Editing, &amp;amp; Replacing MODS Datastreams, post 069, in my blog. In case you missed it, the aforementioned post was written specifically for metadata editors working on the 2020 Grinnell College Libraries review of Digital Grinnell MODS metadata.</description></item><item><title>Exporting, Editing, &amp; Replacing MODS Datastreams</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/069-exporting-editing-replacing-mods-datastreams/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/069-exporting-editing-replacing-mods-datastreams/</guid><description>Attention: On 21-May-2020 an optional, but recommended, sixth step was added to this workflow in the form of a new Drush command: islandora_mods_post_processing, an addition to my previous work in islandora_mods_via_twig. See my new post, Islandora MODS Post Processing for complete details.
The transition to distance learning, social distancing, and more remote work at Grinnell College in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic may afford GC Libraries an opportunity to do some overdue and necessary metadata cleaning in Digital.Grinnell.</description></item></channel></rss>