<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fuse on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/fuse/</link><description>Recent content in Fuse on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:06:51 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/fuse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Searching This Blog Using Fuse</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/110-searching-my-blog-using-fuse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/110-searching-my-blog-using-fuse/</guid><description>&lt;p>A short time ago I moved this blog from &lt;em>DigitalOcean&lt;/em> to &lt;em>Azure&lt;/em>, and along the way I discovered that my &lt;code>search&lt;/code> feature wasn&amp;rsquo;t working properly. That old search mechanism used &lt;a href="https://fusejs.io/">Fuse&lt;/a>, which has NO dependencies, but that old scheme used a &lt;em>Hugo&lt;/em> theme component that I found difficult to properly maintain. So, as this blog was moving to &lt;em>Azure&lt;/em> I elected to try something a little different with &lt;em>Fuse&lt;/em> and found &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/gtrevg/a34e0c736d358771437be05c6401e86c">this gist&lt;/a> to help get it done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As of this writing, the new search is limited to just finding &lt;code>tag&lt;/code> references, and sometimes a search will return a 404 error because of a bad path reference. If you try to search and get the 404 error have a look at the returned URL and if it reads like &lt;code>.../search/search?search-query...&lt;/code> then you&amp;rsquo;ve got one too many instances of the term &lt;code>search&lt;/code>. Remove that first &lt;code>/search&lt;/code> term, including the slash in front of it, and hit return. The search should now return valid results.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>