<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Digital.Grinnell on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>/tags/digital.grinnell/</link><description>Recent content in Digital.Grinnell on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 16:12:55 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/digital.grinnell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Ingest in Digital.Grinnell</title><link>/posts/097-book-ingest-in-digital-grinnell/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 16:12:55 -0600</pubDate><guid>/posts/097-book-ingest-in-digital-grinnell/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s high-time this was posted to my blog, but the canonical copy of this document can be found in smb://Storage/LIBRARY/mcfatem/DG-Book-Ingest-Workflow.md.
Valid Book Datastream Structure I want to begin here by showing what I see as a &amp;ldquo;proper&amp;rdquo; working book datastream structure in Digital.Grinnell. The image below is a screen grab of the datastreams from the Grinnell College Yearbook 1961, DG object grinnell:23749:
Valid Book Datastreams Creating a Valid Book Structure One of the biggest problems I have encountered with ingest of books is uploading very large multi-page PDFs.</description></item><item><title>How to Add a Collection to Digital.Grinnell</title><link>/posts/084-how-to-add-a-collection-to-digital-grinnell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/084-how-to-add-a-collection-to-digital-grinnell/</guid><description>So, you want to add a new collection or sub-collection (they are really the same thing) to Digital.Grinnell, eh? It&amp;rsquo;s easy, but there are some things to consider before I show you how.
Collection Guidelines There are no &amp;ldquo;formal&amp;rdquo; guidelines for the creation of a collection or sub-collection in Digital.Grinnell, but I can think of a couple &amp;ldquo;informal&amp;rdquo; things to consider.
Are there or will there ever be enough objects, old and/or new, with something in common to warrant a new collection?</description></item><item><title>Oral History Transcription Workflow</title><link>/posts/077-oral-history-transcription-workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/077-oral-history-transcription-workflow/</guid><description>Digital.Grinnell features a fair number of transcribed digital oral histories. Most are interviews conducted with Grinnelleans as they return to campus annualy for alumni Reunion or Grinnell&amp;rsquo;s Multicultural Reunion.
What follows is largely sharable &amp;ldquo;public&amp;rdquo; content lifted from a &amp;ldquo;private&amp;rdquo; GitHub repository at https://github.com/McFateM/OHScribe, the README.md and WORKFLOW.md files in particular.
OHScribe! https://ohscribe.grinnell.edu Note: This link was disabled in the spring of 2020, but is working again as of July 1, 2020, on host DGDocker3.
This is a Python 3 and Flask web application designed to transform oral history transcripts, presumably created using InqScribe, into XML suitable for ingest into the Islandora Oral Histories Solution Pack to populate a TRANSCRIPT datastream and its derivatives.</description></item><item><title>Digital.Grinnell Custom MODS Display</title><link>/posts/076-digital.grinnell-custom-mods-display/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/076-digital.grinnell-custom-mods-display/</guid><description>Digital.Grinnell has seen a lot of customization over the years, and quite a bit of it relates to how an object&amp;rsquo;s metadata, especially its MODS metadata, is displayed. My aim for the past couple of years has been to remove as much customization as possible, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found it difficult to remove features of our MODS display because those features seem to be rather popular. This is particulary true of our compound object display.
Custom Compound/Child MODS Display At present, May 28, 2020, the MODS display for a typical compound/child object in Digital.</description></item><item><title>Updating DG's Collection Views</title><link>/posts/068-updating-dgs-collection-views/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/068-updating-dgs-collection-views/</guid><description>Digital.Grinnell employs a custom-built Drupal &amp;ldquo;view&amp;rdquo; we call the dg7 Collection View; it&amp;rsquo;s part of the code in our custom dg7 module where all of Digital.Grinnell&amp;rsquo;s hook implementations are also defined. Experience leads me to beleive that keeping a complex Drupal view in code is prudent, but overriding that code with a database copy of the view helps tremendously in terms of system performance. So, I recommend keeping the view code in the module, but that means that when significant changes are made, like the addition of a new colleciton, the code should be updated in the database to speed things up.</description></item><item><title>Staging Digital.Grinnell (DG) on DigitalOcean (DO)</title><link>/posts/062-testing-dg-staging-on-digitalocean/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/062-testing-dg-staging-on-digitalocean/</guid><description>ISLE v1.3.0 has been running on my staging server, DGDockerX, for months now and it seems to be performing as-expected with one exception&amp;hellip; when I try to import a batch of objects using IMI, the Islandora Multi-Importer, I get the following error:
The website encountered an unexpected error. Please try again later. Examinations of Recent log messages seem to point to DNS issues that I&amp;rsquo;m unable to overcome because I have no control over our DNS records, campus networking, or firewalls.</description></item><item><title>Digital.Grinnell's IMI Workflow</title><link>/posts/040-digital.grinnells-imi-workflow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/040-digital.grinnells-imi-workflow/</guid><description>Note: The abbreviation IMI is used frequently in this post to represent the Islandora Multi-Importer, a CSV-file-driven batch ingest tool used by numerous institutions in the Islandora community.
Also, while updating this post I found this gem&amp;hellip; Diagrams in Documentation (Markdown Guide).
This post is an addition to the discussion in post 028, Mounting //Storage for IMI Ingest in Digital.Grinnell which was written largely to remind me how the //Storage mount works. 😕 Unlike post 028, this post is meant for myself AND for others at Grinnell College who prepare digital objects for ingest via IMI.</description></item><item><title>PDF Ingest in Digital.Grinnell</title><link>/posts/029-pdf-ingest-in-digital-grinnell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 16:56:44 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/029-pdf-ingest-in-digital-grinnell/</guid><description>A set of 21 PDF objects were ingested into Digital.Grinnell&amp;rsquo;s Faculty Scholarship collection using IMI on 22-July-2019; unfortunately none of these PDFs contained OCR (optical character recognition) or &amp;ldquo;text recognition&amp;rdquo; data, so none of them generated a valid FULL_TEXT datastream. FULL_TEXT datastreams are required to make PDF, and similar text content, searchable and discoverable in Digital.Grinnell.
In order to confirm that the lack of OCR was in fact the problem, I ran a little test on https://digital.grinnell.edu/islandora/object/grinnell:26702, one of the 21 objects.</description></item><item><title>Mounting //STORAGE for IMI Ingest in Digital.Grinnell</title><link>/posts/028-mounting-storage-for-imi-ingest-in-digital-grinnell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/028-mounting-storage-for-imi-ingest-in-digital-grinnell/</guid><description>Claiming another small victory today! Why? Well, the Digital.Grinnell instance of IMI (Islandora Multi-Importer) module is customized so that choosing &amp;ldquo;*local&amp;rdquo; as an object ingest source invokes a hook function I created in our DG7 module. That hook enables IMI to &amp;ldquo;find&amp;rdquo; named files/content (things like PDFs, images, etc.) in the Grinnell College //STORAGE server. //STORAGE can be mounted as a CIFS (Common Internet File System) and used to drive ingest if the right package/drivers are made available to Islandora. That can be a little tricky in ISLE, but it&amp;rsquo;s manageable.</description></item></channel></rss>