<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>iduF on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/iduf/</link><description>Recent content in iduF on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/iduf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a Migration Collection</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/129-creating-a-migration-collection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/129-creating-a-migration-collection/</guid><description>As we continue to look at potential migration paths for our Digital.Grinnell (DG) content, it&amp;rsquo;s become apparent that it would be nice to have a small &amp;ldquo;test&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;migration&amp;rdquo; collection of objects to play with. The collection should have a small, but diverse, set of objects covering all of the popular content, or CModel, types that we currently have in DG.
Since Slack now imposes a 90-day lifespan for posts (we are using only free-tier Slack services at this time) I thought I had better create this blog post to capture key parts of a relevant Slack conversation&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Problems with dc:identifier Elements</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/120-problems-with-dcidentifer-elements/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/120-problems-with-dcidentifer-elements/</guid><description>The addition of scholar profiles from LASIR, specifically the module&amp;rsquo;s introduction of /mods/identifier[@type='u1'] and /mods/identifier[@type='u2'] fields, has caused a few problems in Digital.Grinnell. Perhaps the most sinister of these&amp;hellip; these fields are transformed into DC or Dublin Core elements that wreak havoc with our OAI export and subsequent import into Primo VE.
OAI Exports While on the subject of OAI, it&amp;rsquo;s worth noting here that we can query to see the OAI that Digital.Grinnell exported by visiting a URL like: https://digital.</description></item></channel></rss>