<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PDF on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/pdf/</link><description>Recent content in PDF on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/pdf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Here There Be WARCs</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/082-here-there-be-warcs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/082-here-there-be-warcs/</guid><description>The term WARC, an abbreviation of Web ARChive, always reminds me of things like hobbits, elves, dark lords, and orcs, of course. But this post has nothing to do with those things so I need to clear my head and press on.
A WARC is essentially a file format used to capture the content and organization of a web site. Recently, I was asked to add a pair of WARCs to Digital.Grinnell. Doing so proved to be quite an adventure, but I am pleased to report that we now have these two objects to show for it:</description></item><item><title>PDF Ingest in Digital.Grinnell</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/029-pdf-ingest-in-digital-grinnell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 16:56:44 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/029-pdf-ingest-in-digital-grinnell/</guid><description>A set of 21 PDF objects were ingested into Digital.Grinnell&amp;rsquo;s Faculty Scholarship collection using IMI on 22-July-2019; unfortunately none of these PDFs contained OCR (optical character recognition) or &amp;ldquo;text recognition&amp;rdquo; data, so none of them generated a valid FULL_TEXT datastream. FULL_TEXT datastreams are required to make PDF, and similar text content, searchable and discoverable in Digital.Grinnell.
In order to confirm that the lack of OCR was in fact the problem, I ran a little test on https://digital.grinnell.edu/islandora/object/grinnell:26702, one of the 21 objects.</description></item></channel></rss>