<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>static on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/static/</link><description>Recent content in static on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/static/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moving Static Sites to GitHub Pages</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/112-moving-static-sites-to-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/112-moving-static-sites-to-github-pages/</guid><description>Attention: This post effectively superseeds post 109.
Pertinent Resources This section simply tabluates the posts and documentation used to effect migration of all sites from the Grinnell College static host to GitHub Pages.
Resource Address Hugo: Host on GitHub https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-github/ GitHub: Getting started with GitHub Pages https://docs.github.com/en/pages/getting-started-with-github-pages GitHub: Creating a GitHub Pages site https://docs.github.com/en/pages/getting-started-with-github-pages/creating-a-github-pages-site GitHub: Managing a custom domain for your GitHub Pages site https://docs.github.com/en/pages/configuring-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site/managing-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site#configuring-a-subdomain Customizations Do NOT Set publishDir = &amp;quot;docs&amp;quot; Do NOT change the publishDir parameter in your configuration, if you even have one!</description></item><item><title>Searching This Blog Using Fuse</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/110-searching-my-blog-using-fuse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/110-searching-my-blog-using-fuse/</guid><description>A short time ago I moved this blog from DigitalOcean to Azure, and along the way I discovered that my search feature wasn&amp;rsquo;t working properly. That old search mechanism used Fuse, which has NO dependencies, but that old scheme used a Hugo theme component that I found difficult to properly maintain. So, as this blog was moving to Azure I elected to try something a little different with Fuse and found this gist to help get it done.
As of this writing, the new search is limited to just finding tag references, and sometimes a search will return a 404 error because of a bad path reference.</description></item><item><title>Moving Static Sites to Azure</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/109-moving-static-sites-to-azure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/109-moving-static-sites-to-azure/</guid><description>On Thursday, September 9, 2021, I discovered that Azure, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s offering of host/cloud services for Open Source developers, and a favored partner of Grinnell&amp;rsquo;s IT department, had come up with a Static Web App deployment scheme that allegedly would rival what I&amp;rsquo;ve been using at DigitalOcean. So, I first tried to migrate my very simple Static Landing Page Hugo static site to a new home on Azure. The process wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite as slick and easy as at DigitalOcean, but Azure does nicely leverage GitHub Actions, and the process wasn&amp;rsquo;t too difficult to grasp.</description></item><item><title>Repairing Static.Grinnell.edu</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/045-repairing-static.grinnell.edu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/045-repairing-static.grinnell.edu/</guid><description>This morning, Tuesday, September 17, 2019, I awoke to find our https://static.grinnell.edu server, and all of the services on it, unreachable via the web. I managed to open a shell on the host and found that the server was up-and-running as expected, but a quick docker ps command indicated that one of the key services on the server, namely Traefik, had stopped and then failed to restart, repeatedly. Traefik is the service that&amp;rsquo;s responsible for routing web traffic on the static host.</description></item></channel></rss>