<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Submodule on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://digital-grinnell.github.io/dlad-blog/tags/submodule/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Submodule on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:10:25 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://digital-grinnell.github.io/dlad-blog/tags/submodule/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Git Submodule Tips</title>
      <link>https://digital-grinnell.github.io/dlad-blog/posts/100-git-submodule-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:10:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-grinnell.github.io/dlad-blog/posts/100-git-submodule-tips/</guid>
      <description>I seem to have a never-ending struggle with git submodules. Today, I need to add some new features to one of my submodules in a non-ISLE project, but I&amp;rsquo;ve elected to post this here because this blog is relatively easy to search. I also feel fortunate to have found Mastering Git Submodules from Christophe Porteneuve.
So, what I need to do now is update some submodule code, commit, and push that change back to its remote. I will also want to subsequentmly update a pair of projects that use the submodule so they are referencing the newest submodule code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Submodule Workflow in ISLE</title>
      <link>https://digital-grinnell.github.io/dlad-blog/posts/098-git-submodule-workflow-in-isle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 18:23:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-grinnell.github.io/dlad-blog/posts/098-git-submodule-workflow-in-isle/</guid>
      <description>In the past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve attempted to update the &amp;ldquo;staging&amp;rdquo; copy of Digital.Grinnell at https://dg-staging.grinnell.edu and learned a valuable lesson regarding workflow around Git and submodules. Specifically, I found the following resource to be most helpful:
 https://intellipaat.com/community/9971/git-update-submodule-to-latest-commit-on-origin  In case that post ever disappers, here&amp;rsquo;s the gist of it&amp;hellip;
The git submodule update command actually tells git that you simply want your submodules to each check out the commit already mentioned in the index of the superproject.
If you want to update your submodules to the most recent commit available from their remote, you&amp;rsquo;ll try this directly within the submodules.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
