<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DigitalOcean on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/digitalocean/</link><description>Recent content in DigitalOcean on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/digitalocean/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sync Rootstalk Production (DigitalOcean) with Dev</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/116-sync-rootstalk-production-do-with-dev/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/116-sync-rootstalk-production-do-with-dev/</guid><description>My goal for this morning, December 22, 2021, was to find a process I could reliably use to synchronize changes in the development copy of Rootstalk (the main branch https://github.com/Digital-Grinnell/rootstalk) with our production deployment (the main branch of https://github.com/Digital-Grinnell/rootstalk-DO) to DigitalOcean. I used guidance found in How To Merge Between Two Local Repositories to accomplish this with mixed results.
The Workflow I&amp;rsquo;ve captured the inputs and output of the workflow below. The process basically involved adding a new local remote named dev to my existing rootstalk-DO local repository, and doing a git fetch of that new remote.</description></item><item><title>Updates to VAF-Kiosk</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/108-updates-to-vaf-kiosk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/108-updates-to-vaf-kiosk/</guid><description>On Thursday, August 26, 2021, updates to a new iPad destined for the VAF (Visualizing Abolition and Freedom) installing in the Grinnell&amp;rsquo;s HSSC were completed. As of this writing the iPad has not been re-installed, but Facilities Management has been contacted to schedule that event soon.
New DigitalOcean Deployment Due to small differences between the aspect ratio and resolution of the old versus new devices, the kiosk site had to be re-designed. Changes were also necessary to help ensure that users of the kiosk could not &amp;ldquo;escape&amp;rdquo; from the VAF screens and cause havoc by surfing the internet.</description></item><item><title>Staging Digital.Grinnell (DG) on DigitalOcean (DO)</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/062-testing-dg-staging-on-digitalocean/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/062-testing-dg-staging-on-digitalocean/</guid><description>ISLE v1.3.0 has been running on my staging server, DGDockerX, for months now and it seems to be performing as-expected with one exception&amp;hellip; when I try to import a batch of objects using IMI, the Islandora Multi-Importer, I get the following error:
The website encountered an unexpected error. Please try again later. Examinations of Recent log messages seem to point to DNS issues that I&amp;rsquo;m unable to overcome because I have no control over our DNS records, campus networking, or firewalls.</description></item></channel></rss>