<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Traefik on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/traefik/</link><description>Recent content in Traefik on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/traefik/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Traefik and Acme.sh for DG-STAGING</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/093-traefik-and-acme.sh-for-dg-staging/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/093-traefik-and-acme.sh-for-dg-staging/</guid><description>This post is a follow-up to Dockerized Traefik Host Using ACME DNS-01 Challenge and Staging ISLE Installation: Migrate Existing Islandora Site - with Annotations, specifically Step 11 in the later document. It introduces a Digital.Grinnell-specific implementation of the Traefik with Acme.sh.
Testing with McFateM/docker-traefik2-acme-host I started work on this implementation with a test, by cloning https://github.com/McFateM/docker-traefik2-acme-host and proceeding as directed in the repository&amp;rsquo;s README.md document, as user islandora on node DGDockerX, like so:
DGDockerX Host Commands cd ~ git clone https://github.</description></item><item><title>New Host Config: Vulnerability Scan</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/081-new-host-config-vulnerability-scan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/081-new-host-config-vulnerability-scan/</guid><description>Today I elected to run a vulnerability scan against our new instance of the docker-traefik2-acme-host configuration that&amp;rsquo;s running on static.grinnell.edu. The command I used, and the results, are posted below.
╭─islandora@dgdockerx ~ ╰─$ /home/islandora/testssl.sh/testssl.sh static.grinnell.edu ########################################################### testssl.sh 3.0rc4 from https://testssl.sh/dev/ This program is free software. Distribution and modification under GPLv2 permitted. USAGE w/o ANY WARRANTY. USE IT AT YOUR OWN RISK! Please file bugs @ https://testssl.sh/bugs/ ########################################################### Using &amp;#34;OpenSSL 1.0.2-chacha (1.0.2k-dev)&amp;#34; [~183 ciphers] on dgdockerx:/home/islandora/testssl.sh/bin/openssl.Linux.x86_64 (built: &amp;#34;Jan 18 17:12:17 2019&amp;#34;, platform: &amp;#34;linux-x86_64&amp;#34;) Start 2020-06-11 17:33:25 --&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 132.</description></item><item><title>Host Config: docker-traefik2-acme-host</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/080-host-config-docker-traefik2-acme-host/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/080-host-config-docker-traefik2-acme-host/</guid><description>This post is celebrating the completion (really, is anything ever complete?) of a new server/host/stack deployment project: docker-traefik2-acme-host. In order to make this post really easy to read, I&amp;rsquo;m going to wrap it up in one bullet&amp;hellip;
README.md Troubleshooting Should you ever encounter an error like the one below, be sure to ask your IT provider if they created the proper CNAME record when creating your DNS entry.
[Tue Jun 30 20:53:50 UTC 2020] ohscribe.grinnell.edu:Verify error:DNS problem: NXDOMAIN looking up TXT for _acme-challenge.</description></item><item><title>Traefik and Acme.sh Instead of DNS-01</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/079-traefik-and-acme.sh-instead-of-dns-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/079-traefik-and-acme.sh-instead-of-dns-01/</guid><description>This post is a follow-up to Dockerized Traefik Host Using ACME DNS-01 Challenge. It introduces an alternative to the failed process that was proposed in that earlier post.
Note that the following config-specific elements have been replaced below:
6 occurances of ?.grinnell.edu now say example-1.grinnell.edu, and 2 occurances of ?.info now say example-2.info. New Proposal On June 1 my colleage, Matt, suggested the following&amp;hellip;
As much as I would like to resolve the DNS-01 challenge using Traefik alone, I don&amp;rsquo;t believe it will support what we&amp;rsquo;re trying to do here.</description></item><item><title>Simplified Testing of Traefik 2 with ACME DNS-01 Challenge</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/074-simplified-testing-traefik-2-with-acme-dns-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/074-simplified-testing-traefik-2-with-acme-dns-01/</guid><description>This post is a simplified and focused follow-up to Dockerized Traefik Host Using ACME DNS-01 Challenge.
Simplify Today, 19-May-2020, I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a shot at simplifying my testing on dgdocker3.grinnell.edu by removing unnecessary things and consolidating as much as possible to reduce clutter in the logs and get right to the point. I&amp;rsquo;m also going to have a look to see if there are additional logs that can tell give me more detail. Everything used here, and everything that takes place here, will be found in a new directory, /opt/containers/test on DGDocker3.</description></item><item><title>Dockerized Traefik Host Using ACME DNS-01 Challenge</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/071-dockerized-traefik-using-acme-dns-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/071-dockerized-traefik-using-acme-dns-01/</guid><description>This post builds on My dockerized-server Config and attempts to change what was a problematic ACME HTTP-01 or httpChallenge in Traefik and Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt to an ACME DNS-01 or dnsChallenge. The problem with the old HTTP-01 or httpChallenge is that it requires the creation of a valid and widely accessible &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; record in our DNS before the creation of a cert; the record has to be in place so that the Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt CA-server can find it to confirm that the request is valid.</description></item><item><title>Repairing Static.Grinnell.edu</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/045-repairing-static.grinnell.edu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/045-repairing-static.grinnell.edu/</guid><description>This morning, Tuesday, September 17, 2019, I awoke to find our https://static.grinnell.edu server, and all of the services on it, unreachable via the web. I managed to open a shell on the host and found that the server was up-and-running as expected, but a quick docker ps command indicated that one of the key services on the server, namely Traefik, had stopped and then failed to restart, repeatedly. Traefik is the service that&amp;rsquo;s responsible for routing web traffic on the static host.</description></item><item><title>My dockerized-server Config</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/042-my-dockerized-server-config/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/042-my-dockerized-server-config/</guid><description>This post picks up from where Configuring DGDocker2 left off. In it I will establish a workflow to setup a &amp;ldquo;Dockerized&amp;rdquo; server complete with Traefik, Portainer, and Who Am I. It should be relatively easy to add additional non-static services to any server that is initially configured using this package. For &amp;ldquo;static&amp;rdquo; servers have a look at post 008 docker-bootstrap Workflow .
Capture As a Project Picking up from the end of Configuring DGDocker2, my first step on the dgdocker2 server was to move everything into a single subdirectory of /opt; I called the new directory dockerized-server, like so:</description></item><item><title>Configuring DGDocker2</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/041-configuring-dgdocker2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/041-configuring-dgdocker2/</guid><description>My mission today is to successfully migrate the images/containers/services chronicled in post 030, &amp;ldquo;Dockerized Omeka-S: Starting Over&amp;rdquo; to Docker-ready node dgdocker2 without compromising any of the services that already run there.
Pushing WMI Omeka-S to Production on dgdocker2 Grinnell&amp;rsquo;s dgdocker2 server, specifically dgdocker2.grinnell.edu with an IP address of 132.161.132.143, is a Docker-ready CentOS 7 node that&amp;rsquo;s currently supporting the following containers and configuration:
╭─root@dgdocker2 ~ ╰─# docker ps CONTAINER ID IMAGE COMMAND CREATED STATUS PORTS NAMES ef20d71ffea8 mcfatem/ohscribe &amp;#34;./boot.sh&amp;#34; 6 days ago Up 6 days 5000/tcp ohscribe b525f4670cd2 mariadb:latest &amp;#34;docker-entrypoint.</description></item><item><title>Removing Traefik's Weak Cipher Suites</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/005-removing-traefik-weak-ciphers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/005-removing-traefik-weak-ciphers/</guid><description>Most of the servers I deploy to and manage here at Grinnell College are now &amp;ldquo;Dockerized&amp;rdquo;, and all of those use Traefik to manage traffic, of course. Before a web app or server can be opened for access to the world here, it has to pass a vulnerability scan, and I&amp;rsquo;m not privy to the specifics of that scan. However, I do know that &amp;ldquo;weak cipher suites&amp;rdquo; are a common source of failure among my newest servers. It took a couple of weeks of searching, and trial/error solution attempts to identify the nature and specific source of these weaknesses, and to eradicate them.</description></item></channel></rss>