<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lets-Encrypt on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/lets-encrypt/</link><description>Recent content in Lets-Encrypt on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/lets-encrypt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Blog is Born</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/001-a-blog-is-born/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/001-a-blog-is-born/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have you ever wondered how a blog is born? The story behind this blog begins with my interest in stepping back from the CMS world, primarily &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/">Drupal&lt;/a>, to discover the joys of static site generation. The journey begins in earnest at the &lt;a href="https://www.diglib.org/dlf-events/2016forum/">2016 DLF Forum: Milwaukee&lt;/a> on the eve of the United States&amp;rsquo; 2016 national election, when all the buzz that wasn&amp;rsquo;t political, was about building static web sites, and &lt;a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few weeks after the DLF Forum this server was born, thanks to the my colleagues in the &lt;a href="https://www.grinnell.edu/academics/libraries">Grinnell College (GC) Libraries&lt;/a>, and Grinnell&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.grinnell.edu/about/offices-services/its">Information Technology Services (ITS)&lt;/a> department. &lt;em>JekyllDev&lt;/em> was its name, and Jelkyll development was its intended purpose. Life and work quickly got in the way of interests, as they are apt to do, and &lt;em>JekyllDev&lt;/em> subsequently sat idle for nearly 2 years. During that span my work offered opportunities to learn about &amp;lsquo;DevOps&amp;rsquo; technologies like &lt;a href="https://www.ansible.com/">Ansible&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.vagrantup.com/">Vagrant&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.docker.com/">Docker&lt;/a>, and ultimately &lt;a href="https://docksal.io/">Docksal&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>