<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>production on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/production/</link><description>Recent content in production on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/production/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sync Rootstalk Production (DigitalOcean) with Dev</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/116-sync-rootstalk-production-do-with-dev/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/116-sync-rootstalk-production-do-with-dev/</guid><description>My goal for this morning, December 22, 2021, was to find a process I could reliably use to synchronize changes in the development copy of Rootstalk (the main branch https://github.com/Digital-Grinnell/rootstalk) with our production deployment (the main branch of https://github.com/Digital-Grinnell/rootstalk-DO) to DigitalOcean. I used guidance found in How To Merge Between Two Local Repositories to accomplish this with mixed results.
Note: Our staging site cast from the main branch of https://github.com/Digital-Grinnell/rootstalk, an Azure static app, can be accessed via https://icy-tree-020380010.azurestaticapps.net.
The Workflow I&amp;rsquo;ve captured the inputs and output of the workflow below.</description></item><item><title>Production ISLE Installation: Migrate Existing Islandora Site - with Annotations</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/096-production-isle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/096-production-isle/</guid><description>This post is an addendum to earlier post 092. It is intended to chronicle my efforts to complete migration of our production instance of Digital.Grinnell from ISLE v1.1 to ISLE v1.5.1 on Linux node DGDocker1.grinnell.edu. The remainder of this document is an annotated copy of Production ISLE Installation: Migrate Existing Islandora Site.
Annotations, with information specific to my experience with Digital.Grinnell migration, appear in text blocks like this one.
Production ISLE Installation: Migrate Existing Islandora Site Expectations: It takes an average of 2-4+ hours to read this documentation and complete this installation.</description></item></channel></rss>