<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>StatiCrypt on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/staticrypt/</link><description>Recent content in StatiCrypt on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 22:03:49 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/staticrypt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gating My Content &amp; More - Parts 3 and 4</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/141-gating-my-content-and-more-parts-34/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 22:03:49 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/141-gating-my-content-and-more-parts-34/</guid><description>See Gating My Content &amp;amp; More - Parts 1 and 2 for prerequsite and background info.
Introducing Wieting Content Part 3 of this process, the introduction of Wieting Theatre Guild content, is described in the project repo&amp;rsquo;s README.md file. Since the project is in a private repo I&amp;rsquo;ll include the pertinent parts here from this gist.
Part 4 - Protecting Pages with StatiCrypt CLI + More Let&amp;rsquo;s jump in with StatiCrypt CLI. The following experience is from the README.md file in my https://github.</description></item><item><title>Gating My Content &amp; More - Parts 1 and 2</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/139-gating-my-content-and-more/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 18:19:53 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/139-gating-my-content-and-more/</guid><description>A Blended Approach It&amp;rsquo;s a new month, February 2023 that is, and this the first part of follow-up to last month&amp;rsquo;s post in my personal blog, namely Gating My Content. Now, rather than trying to &amp;ldquo;gate&amp;rdquo; some of the content in the Wieting Theatre website, I&amp;rsquo;m going to start a new site, with characteristics listed below, and include only the protected portion of the Wieting&amp;rsquo;s content.
I call this a &amp;ldquo;blended&amp;rdquo; approach because it will, at least initially, leverage and blend guidance and elements from many of the resources I&amp;rsquo;ve captured at https://www.</description></item></channel></rss>