<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LASIR on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/lasir/</link><description>Recent content in LASIR on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 15:12:28 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/lasir/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Everything You Ever Wanted to Know About Digital.Grinnell Entities, but were Afraid to Ask</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/102-digital-grinnell-entities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 15:12:28 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/102-digital-grinnell-entities/</guid><description>Digital.Grinnell used to support and use &amp;ldquo;entities&amp;rdquo;, metadata-only objects that are referential in nature. Entities are best described in this Entities Solution Pack documentation. Quoting from that resource&amp;hellip;
This module allows you to add person, place, event, and organization entities to an Islandora repository. Entities are small, metadata-based objects. A number of forms and additional features are provided in this module for those building an institutional repository with Islandora. Much of the functionality for batch ingest and autocomplete (to use entities as authority objects) centres [sic] around the MADS forms provided with the module.</description></item><item><title>Adding LASIR Features to DG</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/099-adding-lasir-features-to-dg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 15:31:37 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/099-adding-lasir-features-to-dg/</guid><description>This afternoon I finally got back to trying to implement some features of LASIR, the Liberal Arts Sprint for Institutional Repositories. The information I found initially was not what I expected to encounter, and that left me scratching my head just a bit. Fortunately, a colleague at the ICG came through with the needed information and I immediately added it to my list of key resources. You can find those resources in my OneTab at:
https://www.one-tab.com/page/9OatzLo-TB6XuuizqbGrwA And that&amp;rsquo;s a&amp;hellip; break. I hope to add some details, and more links, when I return.</description></item></channel></rss>