<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rootstalk on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/rootstalk/</link><description>Recent content in Rootstalk on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/rootstalk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Export Rootstalk OBJs from Digital.Grinnell</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/117-export-rootstalk-objs-from-dg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/117-export-rootstalk-objs-from-dg/</guid><description>Today&amp;rsquo;s endeavor&amp;hellip; begin the process of moving hundreds of Rootstalk digital objects out of Digital.Grinnell to Azure storage.
Digital.Grinnell Objects Over the last couple of years I have deposited some 477 digital objects, mostly JPEG images and PDFs, into Digital.Grinnell so they could be &amp;ldquo;served&amp;rdquo; up for Rootstalk. I did this because at the time Digital.Grinnell&amp;rsquo;s FEDORA repository was available and relatively easy to use. Unfortunately, DG isn&amp;rsquo;t as reliable or responsive as it once was since its FEDORA is due to be retired in a year or two.</description></item><item><title>Sync Rootstalk Production (DigitalOcean) with Dev</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/116-sync-rootstalk-production-do-with-dev/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/116-sync-rootstalk-production-do-with-dev/</guid><description>My goal for this morning, December 22, 2021, was to find a process I could reliably use to synchronize changes in the development copy of Rootstalk (the main branch https://github.com/Digital-Grinnell/rootstalk) with our production deployment (the main branch of https://github.com/Digital-Grinnell/rootstalk-DO) to DigitalOcean. I used guidance found in How To Merge Between Two Local Repositories to accomplish this with mixed results.
The Workflow I&amp;rsquo;ve captured the inputs and output of the workflow below. The process basically involved adding a new local remote named dev to my existing rootstalk-DO local repository, and doing a git fetch of that new remote.</description></item><item><title>Collaborating on Hugo Site Development</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/095-collaborating-on-hugo-site-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/095-collaborating-on-hugo-site-development/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve nearly completed migration of all Grinnell College Libraries' static sites to Azure and I&amp;rsquo;m updating this post to reflect that move. Wherever possible I&amp;rsquo;ll strike-through outdated information like this, and replace it with updated info.
This post will instruct the reader to install necessary tools and engage the workflow I now use to develop and maintain a handful of Hugo static websites. The list of sites now includes both professional, those owned and operated by Grinnell College, as well as &amp;ldquo;personal&amp;rdquo; sites that I develop, maintain and host myself.</description></item></channel></rss>