<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GitHub Pages on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/github-pages/</link><description>Recent content in GitHub Pages on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/github-pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog Migration Details</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/113-blog-migration-details/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/113-blog-migration-details/</guid><description>The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer&amp;rsquo;s Blog I&amp;rsquo;m getting really lazy in my old age, so what I&amp;rsquo;ve posted here is just the meager README.md file from my blog&amp;rsquo;s new GitHub repo.
This project, my Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer&amp;rsquo;s blog, is no longer a Docker &amp;ldquo;Multi-Stage&amp;rdquo; build.
GitHub Pages I successfully moved this blog to GitHub Pages in October 2021, after creating instances of it on DigitalOcean and Azure. GH Pages, specifically https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/ seems like the right home for it, finally.</description></item><item><title>Moving Static Sites to GitHub Pages</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/112-moving-static-sites-to-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/112-moving-static-sites-to-github-pages/</guid><description>Pertinent Resources This section simply tabluates the posts and documentation used to effect migration of all sites from the Grinnell College static host to GitHub Pages.
Resource Address Hugo: Host on GitHub https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-github/ GitHub: Getting started with GitHub Pages https://docs.github.com/en/pages/getting-started-with-github-pages GitHub: Creating a GitHub Pages site https://docs.github.com/en/pages/getting-started-with-github-pages/creating-a-github-pages-site GitHub: Managing a custom domain for your GitHub Pages site https://docs.github.com/en/pages/configuring-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site/managing-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site#configuring-a-subdomain Customizations Do NOT Set publishDir = &amp;quot;docs&amp;quot; Do NOT change the publishDir parameter in your configuration, if you even have one! The default public setting is correct.</description></item></channel></rss>