<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog Migration Details</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/113-blog-migration-details/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/113-blog-migration-details/</guid><description>The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer&amp;rsquo;s Blog I&amp;rsquo;m getting really lazy in my old age, so what I&amp;rsquo;ve posted here is just the meager README.md file from my blog&amp;rsquo;s new GitHub repo.
This project, my Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer&amp;rsquo;s blog, is no longer a Docker &amp;ldquo;Multi-Stage&amp;rdquo; build.
GitHub Pages I successfully moved this blog to GitHub Pages in October 2021, after creating instances of it on DigitalOcean and Azure. GH Pages, specifically https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/ seems like the right home for it, finally.</description></item><item><title>New Blog Style and Features</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/067-new-blog-style-and-features/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/067-new-blog-style-and-features/</guid><description>Welcome to my new blog theme/style with new features. All of the content, aka &amp;lsquo;posts&amp;rsquo;, from my old blog have been moved here, but there are still lots of remnants of the new theme, Zzo, lurking here. Please be patient with this new format while I work to fully implement all the features that this setup provides.
Also, thank you, Mackenzie. My daughter played an important role in helping me with this transition.
And it&amp;rsquo;s time to do some real work&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll be back to share more here soon.</description></item></channel></rss>