<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Oh My ZSH! on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/oh-my-zsh/</link><description>Recent content in Oh My ZSH! on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/oh-my-zsh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing ZSH in Catalina</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/063-installing-zsh-in-catalina/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/063-installing-zsh-in-catalina/</guid><description>These days I like to do all my terminal/command-line work in zsh, more specifically, with Oh My ZSH! and the bira theme. This previous post described the process I used on each of my Linux servers, and this post is similar, but written specifically for my Catalina (Macintosh OS X v10.15.x), workstations.
This is how I installed and configured zsh, and some other goodies, on my student Mac Mini workstation, MA6879&amp;hellip;
brew update brew install nano zsh chsh -s /bin/zsh mark exit # log back in after this echo $SHELL brew install wget git hugo docker # Docker and Hugo added just for good measure wget https://github.</description></item><item><title>Installing ZSH in CentOS</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/044-installing-zsh-in-centos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/044-installing-zsh-in-centos/</guid><description>These days I like to do all my terminal/command-line work in zsh, more specifically, with Oh My ZSH! and the bira theme. So, on my new node dgdocker3, I added nano, zsh, and some other goodies by largely following How to Setup ZSH and Oh-my-zsh on Linux.
This is how I did it&amp;hellip;
sudo yum install nano sudo yum install zsh chsh -s /bin/zsh mcfatem exit # log back in after this echo $SHELL sudo yum install wget git wget https://github.</description></item></channel></rss>