<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Migrate on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>/tags/migrate/</link><description>Recent content in Migrate on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/migrate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Production ISLE Installation: Migrate Existing Islandora Site - with Annotations</title><link>/posts/096-production-isle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/096-production-isle/</guid><description>Attention: Take note that annotations stop where my process departed from this script in Step 16. Enter at your own risk beyond the annotation in Step 16!
-- This post is an addendum to earlier post 092. It is intended to chronicle my efforts to complete migration of our production instance of Digital.Grinnell from ISLE v1.1 to ISLE v1.5.1 on Linux node DGDocker1.grinnell.edu. The remainder of this document is an annotated copy of Production ISLE Installation: Migrate Existing Islandora Site.</description></item><item><title>Traefik and Acme.sh for DG-STAGING</title><link>/posts/093-traefik-and-acme.sh-for-dg-staging/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/093-traefik-and-acme.sh-for-dg-staging/</guid><description>This post is a follow-up to Dockerized Traefik Host Using ACME DNS-01 Challenge and Staging ISLE Installation: Migrate Existing Islandora Site - with Annotations, specifically Step 11 in the later document. It introduces a Digital.Grinnell-specific implementation of the Traefik with Acme.sh.
Testing with McFateM/docker-traefik2-acme-host I started work on this implementation with a test, by cloning https://github.com/McFateM/docker-traefik2-acme-host and proceeding as directed in the repository&amp;rsquo;s README.md document, as user islandora on node DGDockerX, like so:
DGDockerX Host Commands cd ~ git clone https://github.</description></item><item><title>Staging ISLE Installation: Migrate Existing Islandora Site - with Annotations</title><link>/posts/092-staging-isle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/092-staging-isle/</guid><description>Attention: Take note that annotations stop where my process departed from this script in Step 16. Enter at your own risk beyond the annotation in Step 16!
This post is an addendum to earlier posts 087 and 090. It is intended to chronicle my efforts to migrate to a staging instance of Digital.Grinnell on Linux node DGDockerX.grinnell.edu. The remainder of this document is an annotated copy of Staging ISLE Installation: Migrate Existing Islandora Site.
Annotations, with information specific to my experience with Digital.</description></item><item><title>Local ISLE Installation: Migrate Existing Islandora Site - One-Time Customizations</title><link>/posts/090-isle-local-migration-customization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/090-isle-local-migration-customization/</guid><description>This post is an addendum to earlier post 087. It is intended to chronicle my customization efforts, necessary steps that follow the aforementioned document&amp;rsquo;s Step 11, to migrate to a local development instance of Digital.Grinnell on my work-issued iMac, MA8660, currently identified as MAD25W812UJ1G9. Please refer to Steps 0 - 11 in post 087 for background info.
Note that it should NOT be necessary to repeat steps taken in this document. Pertinent changes made herein were saved into a new completed-install-local-migrate branch of my dg-islandora project repository, effectively capturing all progress made within.</description></item><item><title>Local ISLE Installation: Migrate Existing Islandora Site - with Annotations</title><link>/posts/087-rebuilding-isle-ld-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/087-rebuilding-isle-ld-again/</guid><description>This post is an addendum to earlier posts 021 and 058, with simiar titles. It is intended to chronicle my efforts to migrate to a local development instance of Digital.Grinnell on my work-issued iMac, MA8660, currently identified as MAD25W812UJ1G9.
Goal The goal of this project is once again to spin up a local Islandora stack using the ISLE project following the guidance of the project&amp;rsquo;s install-local-migrate document. My process will be slightly different than documented since I&amp;rsquo;ve already created a pair of private dg-isle and dg-islandora repositories.</description></item><item><title>Granular ISLE Customization: Install 'Backup and Migrate'</title><link>/posts/057-granular-isle-customization-instal-backup-and-migrate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/057-granular-isle-customization-instal-backup-and-migrate/</guid><description>Granular ISLE Customization This post is part of a series describing Digital.Grinnell customizations to ISLE, in a &amp;ldquo;granular&amp;rdquo; format&amp;hellip; one small customization at a time. An index of all documents in this series is included at the end of Granular ISLE Customization: Series Guidelines. Goal Statement In this &amp;ldquo;granular&amp;rdquo; post we will install Backup and Migrate, a tremendous Drupal module that I use extensively for backup, restoration, migration and maintenance of Digital.</description></item></channel></rss>