<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fuse.js on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>/tags/fuse.js/</link><description>Recent content in Fuse.js on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/fuse.js/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Searching This Blog Using Fuse</title><link>/posts/110-searching-my-blog-using-fuse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/110-searching-my-blog-using-fuse/</guid><description>A short time ago I moved this blog from DigitalOcean to Azure, and along the way I discovered that my search feature wasn&amp;rsquo;t working properly. That old search mechanism used Fuse, which has NO dependencies, but that old scheme used a Hugo theme component that I found difficult to properly maintain. So, as this blog was moving to Azure I elected to try something a little different with Fuse and found this gist to help get it done.
As of this writing, the new search is limited to just finding tag references, and sometimes a search will return a 404 error because of a bad path reference.</description></item><item><title>Back in (Scarlet and) Black</title><link>/posts/083-back-in-scarlet-and-black/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/083-back-in-scarlet-and-black/</guid><description>Once upon a time this blog had an address of https://static.grinnell.edu/blogs/McFateM and it used a theme called M10c. Well, what was once is once again. If you read my New Blog Style and Features post you can learn a little more of this blog&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;interim&amp;rdquo; history.
By the way, if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this post at https://dlad.summittdweller.com, then you&amp;rsquo;re missing out. If you are looking at that old blog you probably see something more like this:
Please jump to https://static.grinnell.edu/blogs/McFateM and catch up as quick as you can!</description></item></channel></rss>