<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>backup on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://digital-grinnell.github.io/dlad-blog/tags/backup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in backup on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://digital-grinnell.github.io/dlad-blog/tags/backup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Granular ISLE Customization: Install &#39;Backup and Migrate&#39;</title>
      <link>https://digital-grinnell.github.io/dlad-blog/posts/057-granular-isle-customization-instal-backup-and-migrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-grinnell.github.io/dlad-blog/posts/057-granular-isle-customization-instal-backup-and-migrate/</guid>
      <description>Granular ISLE Customization     This post is part of a series describing Digital.Grinnell customizations to ISLE, in a &amp;ldquo;granular&amp;rdquo; format&amp;hellip; one small customization at a time.   An index of all documents in this series is included at the end of Granular ISLE Customization: Series Guidelines.    Goal Statement In this &amp;ldquo;granular&amp;rdquo; post we will install Backup and Migrate, a tremendous Drupal module that I use extensively for backup, restoration, migration and maintenance of Digital.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Omeka-S Data to NFS</title>
      <link>https://digital-grinnell.github.io/dlad-blog/posts/054-moving-omeka-s-data-to-nfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-grinnell.github.io/dlad-blog/posts/054-moving-omeka-s-data-to-nfs/</guid>
      <description>Grinnell&amp;rsquo;s dockerized version of Omeka-S has been running for several weeks now, and we recently ran out of disk space for object data on the host, a CentOS node we named DGDocker2. My posts 041, Configuring DGDocker2 and 042, My dockerized-server Config address the original configuration of DGDocker2 in detail.
Omeka-S is configured on DGDocker2 to reside in /opt/omeka-s-docker, and inside that directory is a subdirectory named volume. The portions of the application stack that deliver Omeka-S are configured largely in /opt/omeka-s-docker/docker-compose.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
