<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/azure/</link><description>Recent content in Azure on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 10:36:03 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating Better Documentation</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/138-creating-better-documentation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 10:36:03 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/138-creating-better-documentation/</guid><description>We Need More Cow Bell Screen Capture! On a recent project I found myself following some development guidance provided in Deploying an 11ty Site to Azure Static Web Apps and I really like the work that squalrus did here because there&amp;rsquo;s a nice mix of screen capture images and descriptive text. I think my documentation, at least in the past, has been lacking in images. Time to fix that.
Command - Shift - 5 On my Mac I frequently use the command - shift - 5 key sequence to launch dynamic &amp;ndash; think movie, not image &amp;ndash; screen capture.</description></item><item><title>Gating My Content AND More</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/139-gating-my-content-and-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 13:20:49 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/139-gating-my-content-and-more/</guid><description>A Blended Approach It&amp;rsquo;s a new month, February 2023 that is, and this is follow-up to last month&amp;rsquo;s post in my personal blog, namely Gating My Content. Now, rather than trying to &amp;ldquo;gate&amp;rdquo; some of the content in the Wieting Theatre website, I&amp;rsquo;m going to start a new site, with characteristics listed below, with just the protected portion of the Wieting&amp;rsquo;s content involved.
I call this a &amp;ldquo;blended&amp;rdquo; approach because it will, at least initially, leverage and blend guidance and elements from many of the resources I&amp;rsquo;ve captured at https://www.</description></item><item><title>Migrating CATPAW Development to Azure</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/135-migrating-catpaw-development-to-azure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/135-migrating-catpaw-development-to-azure/</guid><description>Portions of this post build on concepts introduced in Managing Azure.
CATPAW - Computer-Aided Thinking, Primarily about Writing From the CATPAW home screen&amp;hellip;
In many ways, CATPAW is an online book about writing style&amp;ndash;a guide to the choices we make in writing that connect us to our readers.
Rather than setting out rules to follow, CATPAW will help you make informed choices in context. The site accomplishes that goal in three ways:
It explains the choices writers face. It uses computational tools to help you examine your own writing, letting you see what choices you have already made and what you might want to do differently.</description></item><item><title>Managing Azure</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/130-managing-azure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/130-managing-azure/</guid><description>For the past couple years I/we have been experimenting with moving digital content to Azure, both for storage and as a web app host. The most prominent case is with regard to Rootstalk where Azure currently supports two (recently down from three) static development apps as well as a storage account. All such services are part of a personal* Azure subscription opened under the digital@grinnell.edu email address.
*I call this a &amp;ldquo;personal&amp;rdquo; account because charges for it are currently billed to my own credit card, a situation that will need to be changed sometime relatively soon.</description></item><item><title>Moving Static Sites to Azure</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/109-moving-static-sites-to-azure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/109-moving-static-sites-to-azure/</guid><description>On Thursday, September 9, 2021, I discovered that Azure, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s offering of host/cloud services for Open Source developers, and a favored partner of Grinnell&amp;rsquo;s IT department, had come up with a Static Web App deployment scheme that allegedly would rival what I&amp;rsquo;ve been using at DigitalOcean. So, I first tried to migrate my very simple Static Landing Page Hugo static site to a new home on Azure. The process wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite as slick and easy as at DigitalOcean, but Azure does nicely leverage GitHub Actions, and the process wasn&amp;rsquo;t too difficult to grasp.</description></item></channel></rss>