<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wieting on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/wieting/</link><description>Recent content in Wieting on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 18:19:53 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/tags/wieting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gating My Content &amp; More - Parts 1 and 2</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/139-gating-my-content-and-more/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 18:19:53 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/139-gating-my-content-and-more/</guid><description>A Blended Approach It&amp;rsquo;s a new month, February 2023 that is, and this the first part of follow-up to last month&amp;rsquo;s post in my personal blog, namely Gating My Content. Now, rather than trying to &amp;ldquo;gate&amp;rdquo; some of the content in the Wieting Theatre website, I&amp;rsquo;m going to start a new site, with characteristics listed below, and include only the protected portion of the Wieting&amp;rsquo;s content.
I call this a &amp;ldquo;blended&amp;rdquo; approach because it will, at least initially, leverage and blend guidance and elements from many of the resources I&amp;rsquo;ve captured at https://www.</description></item><item><title>How to Create a New GitHub Repo from an Existing Branch</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/065-create-new-github-project-from-a-branch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/065-create-new-github-project-from-a-branch/</guid><description>I just found a handy git/GitHub workflow in a Quora post titled &amp;ldquo;How do I create a new GitHub repository from a branch in an existing repository?&amp;rdquo;. And I used it, successfully, to create a new GitHub repo for my updated Drupal 8 rendition of the Wieting Theatre&amp;rsquo;s website.
The new GitHub repo is wieting-D8-DO and it was created from the wieting branch of docker-compose-drupal.
The commands I used looked something like this:
cd ~/GitHub git clone https://github.com/SummittDweller/docker-compose-drupal.git cd docker-compose-drupal git checkout master git reset --hard origin/wieting git checkout wieting git remote rm origin git remote add origin https://github.</description></item><item><title>Migration to Lando</title><link>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/064-migration-to-lando/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://static.grinnell.edu/dlad-blog/posts/064-migration-to-lando/</guid><description>I have ITS tickets, for seemingly simple DNS changes, that are now more than a month old, and because of that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken steps to try and do some ISLE staging work on one of my DigitalOcean droplets, namely summitt-services-droplet-01. In order to accommodate that I&amp;rsquo;ve moved nearly all of the sites and services from that droplet to my other, summitt-dweller-DO-docker. The site migration was a smooth process except for https://Wieting.TamaToledo.com. That Drupal 8 site has been difficult to upgrade and migrate largely because it was deployed using my old Port-Ability scripts, and about a year ago I scrapped Port-Ability in favor of Docksal, but I never got around to moving that particular site to a Docksal environment.</description></item></channel></rss>