<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>staging on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</title><link>/tags/staging/</link><description>Recent content in staging on The Grinnell College Digital Library Application Developer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/staging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Traefik and Acme.sh for DG-STAGING</title><link>/posts/093-traefik-and-acme.sh-for-dg-staging/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/093-traefik-and-acme.sh-for-dg-staging/</guid><description>This post is a follow-up to Dockerized Traefik Host Using ACME DNS-01 Challenge and Staging ISLE Installation: Migrate Existing Islandora Site - with Annotations, specifically Step 11 in the later document. It introduces a Digital.Grinnell-specific implementation of the Traefik with Acme.sh.
Testing with McFateM/docker-traefik2-acme-host I started work on this implementation with a test, by cloning https://github.com/McFateM/docker-traefik2-acme-host and proceeding as directed in the repository&amp;rsquo;s README.md document, as user islandora on node DGDockerX, like so:
DGDockerX Host Commands cd ~ git clone https://github.</description></item><item><title>Staging ISLE Installation: Migrate Existing Islandora Site - with Annotations</title><link>/posts/092-staging-isle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/092-staging-isle/</guid><description>Attention: Take note that annotations stop where my process departed from this script in Step 16. Enter at your own risk beyond the annotation in Step 16!
This post is an addendum to earlier posts 087 and 090. It is intended to chronicle my efforts to migrate to a staging instance of Digital.Grinnell on Linux node DGDockerX.grinnell.edu. The remainder of this document is an annotated copy of Staging ISLE Installation: Migrate Existing Islandora Site.
Annotations, with information specific to my experience with Digital.</description></item><item><title>Staging Digital.Grinnell (DG) on DigitalOcean (DO)</title><link>/posts/062-testing-dg-staging-on-digitalocean/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/062-testing-dg-staging-on-digitalocean/</guid><description>ISLE v1.3.0 has been running on my staging server, DGDockerX, for months now and it seems to be performing as-expected with one exception&amp;hellip; when I try to import a batch of objects using IMI, the Islandora Multi-Importer, I get the following error:
The website encountered an unexpected error. Please try again later. Examinations of Recent log messages seem to point to DNS issues that I&amp;rsquo;m unable to overcome because I have no control over our DNS records, campus networking, or firewalls.</description></item><item><title>Pushing ISLE to Staging</title><link>/posts/059-pushing-isle-to-staging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/059-pushing-isle-to-staging/</guid><description>This post chronicles the steps I took to push my local dg.localdomain project, an ISLE v1.3.0 build, to staging on node DGDockerX as https://isle-stage.grinnell.edu using my dg-isle and dg-islandora repositories.
Directories I&amp;rsquo;ll begin by opening a terminal on the staging host, DGDockerX as user islandora. Then I very carefully (note the use of the --recursive flags!) clone the aforementioned projects to DGDockerX like so:
Host / DGDockerX Commands cd /opt git clone &amp;ndash;recursive https://github.</description></item></channel></rss>